A Guide to the Glasgow Family Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10137-a
Glasgow Family Collection 1899-1976 (bulk 1899-1940)
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10137-a
ca. 175 items
Josephine Glasgow Clark
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Miss Josephine Glasgow Clark, 15 July 1976
Container List
- Correspondence
  - Cary Glasgow McCormack to Annie Glasgow Clark, [ante 1899] June 7; ALS, 6 p. on 2 1.
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(Milan, Italy) to Josephine Glasgow Clark(showing Ellen Glasgow coming out of the Coptic church in Cairo, Egypt), 1899 May 14; APCS
  - Cary Glasgow McCormack to Annie Glasgow Clark, from abroad, 1899-1910; 20 APC
  - Cary Glasgow McCormack to Josephine Glasgow Clark, from abroad, 1899-1924; 15 APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Mürren, Switzerland) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1903 Aug 13-14; APCS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(St. Malo, France) to Frank T. Glasgow, 1903 Sept 6 & 7; APC
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Josephine Glasgow Clark, written while Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler was travelling with Ellen Glasgow in Europe, 1903-1906 [1924]; 58 APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Bremen, Germany) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1904 July 27; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Wiesbaden, Germany) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1904 Aug 24; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Dresden, Germany) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1904 Aug 27; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Chamonix, France) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1904 Sept 12; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Prague, Czechoslovakia) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1904 Sept 14]; APCS
  - Otto B. Plötz(Nordhausen, Germany) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1905 July 18; APCS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(Nordhausen, Germany) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1905 July 18; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Dresden, Germany) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1905 July 19; APCS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(Karlsbad, Germany) to [ Josephine Glasgow Clark], 1905 July 24; APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Vienna, Austria) to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1905 July 25; APCS
  - Otto B. Plötz(Tilsit, Germany) to Ellen Glasgow, 1905 Aug 14; APCS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(Verona, Italy) to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1905 Aug 29; APCS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(Bern, Switzerland) to Annie Glasgow Clark, [ca. 1905] Aug 29; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Florence, Italy) to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1905 Sept 3; APCS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler(Perugia, Italy) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1905 Sept 13; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Sienna, Italy) to Cary Glasgow McCormack, [1905?] Sept 16; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Quebec, Canada) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1906 Sept 7]; APC
  - Cary Glasgow McCormack(Naples, Italy) to "Miss Glasgow", 1907 Sept 6; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Borca, Italy) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1908 May 24; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Rome, Italy) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1908 Aug 3; APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Assisi, Italy) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1908 Aug 4 & 5; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Borca, Italy) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1908 Aug 11; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Borca, Italy) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1908 Aug 14; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Borca, Italy) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1908 Aug 23; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Borca, Italy) to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1908 Aug 27; APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Naples, Italy) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1908 Sept 13; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(La Cava, Italy) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1908 Sept 14; APCS
  - Cary Glasgow McCormack to Frank T. Glasgow, from Italy, 1908; 4 APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Dorking, England) to Cary Glasgow McCormack, 1909 Apr 22; APCS
  - P. G. Gerom(Florence, Italy) to Ellen Glasgow, 1909 [Dec 2]; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Paris, France) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1910 Apr 13; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Lausanne, Switzerland) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1910 Apr 15; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Lugano, Switzerland) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1910 May 16; APCS
  - Louise Collier Willcox(London, England) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1914 May 28]; APC
  - Ellen Glasgow(Eton College, England) to Annie Glasgow Clark, 1914 May 31; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Dorset, England) to Annie Glasgow Clark, [1914 June 6]; APCS
  - Louise Collier Willcox(Dorchester, England) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1914 Summer]; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Naples, Italy) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1915?] May 23; APCS
  - Annie Glasgow Clark to Glasgow Clark, [1916 Feb 2]; ALS, 6 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark(With telegram, 1925 Nov 6, "Jereny" [Jeremy] and "Billy" (Ellen Glasgow's dogs) to Josephine Glasgow Clark), [1925 Nov 5]; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1925 Apr 29]; ALS, 4 p. on 2 1., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1926 Nov 8]; ALS, 2 p. on 1 1., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow(Harrogate, England) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1927 July 13; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Harrogate, England) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1927 July 26; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow(Lincoln, England) to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1927 Aug 3; ALS, 5 p. on 3 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1929 May 6]; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1930 June 18; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1932 Dec 20]; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1933 Aug 29]; TL, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1936 Feb 18]; TL, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1936 Apr 16]; TLS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1939 Dec 30; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1940 June 13; TLS, 1 p. on 1 1., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1940 July 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Anne Virginia Bennett to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1940 Dec; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Souvenir folder of postcards of Castine, Maine, addressed to Josephine Glasgow Clark in the hand of Ellen Glasgow, [1914 Sept 22]
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1942 June 3; TL, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1942 Dec 19; ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1943 June 23; TL, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1944 May 6; TL, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, [1944 May 28]; TL, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Arthur Graham Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1953 Jan 10; TLS
  - Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler to Josephine Glasgow Clark, 1967 Jan 4; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Ellen Glasgow(London, England) to Annie Glasgow Clark, May 26; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow to Josephine Glasgow Clark, n.d. [Sunday]; TL, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Notes by Josephine Glasgow Clark regarding the correspondents in this collection (collection 10137-a). A few other notes by Miss Clark appear throughout with the material to which they pertain., 1976 July; 5 AN